welcome back
today we are going to make some rocket fuel
and the first step is to make phthalic acid
which is made with potassium dichromate
this can be made in many ways
but the fastest one requires a ZPM chemical reactor
since we don't even have access to LuV
we shall do that by using 8 IV energy hatches
once we have fully charged the batteries for that setup
we can see that this thing doesn't work
and thus
we shall have two additional small reactors
to soften the process requirements
and now we can get the potassium dichromate
for the ferric acid
fermentic acid has many usages
and the first one we will want to do
is to make diphosphoric acid
which is one of the two ingredients
needed for making polybenzimidazole
also known as PBI
the other ingredient is 3,3-diaminobenzidine
which can easily be synthesized from 3,3-dichlorobenzidine
which we make out of 2-Nitro chlorobenzene
now that we have PBI
we can assemble a better Thermal Protection
which will help us survive the harsh outer space exploration
that we will do with our new rocket
but it looks like we have forgotten something
the reason why we made ferric acid was not for PBI
but for rocket fuel
so we go back to dehydrating some of it
to get some phthalic anhydride
we bring that to our chemical plant
where we react it with ethylbenzene
to get some 2-ethylanthraquinone
since that is a catalyst
we get that fluid to an automated setup
for further processing
this chemical plant is going to self feed on itself a lot of its products
but let's see them one at a time
first
we turn the 2-ethylanthraquinone into 2-ethylanthrahydroquinone
which we use to make hydrogen peroxide
that will also give back some 2-ethylanthraquinone
finally we add some other stuff to make hydrazine
and here we have all the inputs
now all we have to do is to push the start button
and once the hydrazine is produced
we can retrieve it from our main terminal
we manually add some methanol to obtain dense hydrazine
which is a fuel rocket that can work with our tier 3 rocket
and once we loaded our new rocket
we can take off to the new planets and moons
and the main destination is going to be Ceres
where we can find platinum veins
while we wait for our miners
we can do the last chemical chain of the IV Quest page
monazite
this chemical line requires some crush ores
which we are already processing in other ways
to ensure it gets to that line
we use a high priority storage bus on a drawer
and here
instead of the usual mineral processing machines
we use a digester to digest those heavy rocks
the output then goes into a dissolution tank
and this machine requires the inputs to have a specific ratio to be able to work
so we are going to move the fluids slowly and steady steps
with covers that will control the level inside the hatches
and this seems to work as intended
by stopping once we reach 9 metric cubes of fluid
we do the same with the other input
and once we have properly regulated the fluid inputs
we can start the second processing step in the dissolution tank
the output has to be sifted to get a lot of products
but the one we care the most is the monazite sulfate dust
which we bath in some acid
then we sift it again
we give it a quick dry in a blast furnace
we react with nitric acid
we mix in some other chemicals
then we run that poor compound in a sifter one more time
and we vacuum freeze the outputs
using the new upcoming polarizer in electromagnetic separator mode
we take out stuff that may not even be ferromagnetic
we reuse the previous EBF to extract
heterogeneous halogenic monazite rare earth mixture dust
we mix it with other stuff up to its saturation point
and then I guess we separate what we just mixed in
from which we can finally sift out some samarium
this is going to be required for the motors of the next tier
we followed the main processing path
but there are some byproduct we have left behind
so we shall gather those too
but we mostly reused the same machines
and we shall also do the bastnasite line
since we are doing weird mineral lines
this is more streamlined
and the main output is holmium
we are once again
going to reuse as many machines as possible
now we can go back to Ceres to retrieve our platinum
and once back
we find a nice surprise
we also have gathered some naquadah
which will allow us to start one more funny chemical line
unlike the previous artificial chemical processing
this line is going to be more based on fantasy and imagination
we start by preparing some shaved ice
then we add some Antimony aroma
but they added too much flavor
and now it look like one of the previous chemicals
so we try to distill it
to see how much more we can concentrate the aroma
but we want it to be slightly sour
so we make it more acid
and now
it is the perfect moment to add in the main ingredient
the naquadah
after heating it
we centrifuge out some of the residue of the artificial aroma
now this is still low quality
so we have to add some seasoning such as P-507
and as you can see
our naquadah is no longer low quality
since we have used some good P-507
made by manually farming some organic nuts
for its oil component
the last touch is to activate the neutrons inside our dish
to make it feel funny on the tongue
however
we do not have the cooking tools required for such tasks
to make one
we need a precision assembler
but to make a precision assembler
we need some dope naquadah wafers
the convenience store doesn't keep them
so we have to go with the poors man way of making naquadah
and with those small amounts made in an ugly way
we have just enough for our precision assembler
however
that was just the controller block
we also need a stack of the casings
and here we run into an issue
we need an LuV assembler
so I guess we should go back on track
and start working on the assembly line for the Luv tier
but I think this deserves its own episode
bye bye
欢迎回来！
今天我们要做一些火箭燃料
第一步是用重铬酸钾粉
来制造邻苯二甲酸
制作出重铬酸钾的方法多多
而最有效率的需要 ZPM 化学反应釜
由于 LuV 级别我们都未曾涉足
我们将通过八仓升压来达到 ZPM 级
即使我们将电池全部充满
机器还是无法正常工作
因此
我们再用两个小化反进行额外反应
用来降低大化反配方要求
现在我们便得到了
用于制作邻苯二甲酸的重铬酸钾
邻苯二甲酸大有其用
第一个用处
便是制作间苯二甲酸二苯酯
而这是制作聚苯并咪唑所需的
两种必备材料之一
它简称为 PBI
另一种材料是 3,3-二氨基联苯胺
通过 3,3-二氯联苯胺便可轻松获取
而我们使用 2-硝基氯苯制造它
现在我们有了 PBI
一套更加优秀的隔热装置便呼之欲出
这将帮助我们使用新火箭进行太空探索时
保护我们安然无恙
但我们似乎好像遗漏了什么事情
我们不是为了 PBI 来制造邻苯二甲酸
而是为了火箭燃料
所以让我们回去进行脱水
来获得点邻苯二甲酸酐粉
我们把它带到化工厂
让它和乙苯发生反应
于是便获得了 2-乙基蔥醌
此流体将在反应中完全循环
我们将液体导入一个自动化过程
用于进一步处理
这个化工厂将自给自足许多产品
但是让我们聚焦于其中一种
第一步
我们将 2-乙基蒽菎变成 2-乙基蒽氢菎
它将用于制作过氧化氢
此过程也会返还一些 2-乙基蒽菎
最后加入一些其他东西来制造肼
这便是所有的原料输入仓
唯一要做的便是开机
一旦肼开始生产
我们可以从 ME 终端中直接拿取
我们手动加入一些甲醇得到密集肼火箭燃料
而这是能在 T3 火箭中使用的一种燃料
一旦新火箭的燃料完成填充
新的行星卫星便不再遥远
我们主要目的地是谷神星
在那里可以找到铂矿脉
在等待矿机完成工作的同时
我们着手于 IV 任务的最后一条化学链
独居石处理
这条化学生产线需要一些粉碎矿
而我们已用其他方法完成处理
为了确保它们进入这条产线
我们将抽屉上的存储总线调成最优先
还有这里
不同于平常的矿处机器
我们将用煮解池来进行处理
输出物将进入溶解罐
而这台机器要求输入流体具有特殊比例
所以要精准且缓慢地输入它们
而流体探测覆盖板能胜任这份工作
一旦输入仓有了 9 kL 液体
它便停止抽取
我们对另一个输入仓故技重施
一旦液体输入调整完毕
第二个步骤便可以顺利进行
输出物必须经过筛选才能获得大量产物
而我们最关心的便是硫酸独居石粉
将其用硝酸洗个澡
再筛选一次
高炉中快速烘烤
再与硝酸反应一次
然后加上其他化学反应物
又又筛选一次
随后将其冷冻
使用磁通量效应监视器中电磁离析模式
来剔除那些非铁磁性的成分
我们复用之前的高炉提取出
异质卤化独居石稀土混合物粉
我们把它与其他物品搅拌至饱和
再通入离心机分开
再筛出少量钐粉
而这是下一电压中马达的必需品
我们做完了镧系处理的主线
但还有些支线没做
接着干
我们打算重复利用大部分机器
既然在做奇怪的矿物处理了
我们不妨继续做氟碳铈矿处理
这条产线更像流水线
而它的主要输出是狄粉
我们将又一次
尽可能地多重复利用机器
现在我们回谷神星取回铂矿
一回到家
我们便发现了一个惊喜
我们还收集到了一些硅岩矿
这将开启一条更有趣的化学产线
不像之前存在于现实的产线
这条产线将更多基于奇思妙想
首先准备一些碎冰
再加入些许锑粉
但由于添加太多化学物
现在它看起来像以前的化学物质之一
所以我们对其进行蒸馏
看看能浓缩到什么地步
但我们希望它酸一点
所以我们让它显酸性
而现在
是添加主要成分的最佳时机
氧化硅岩混合物粉
通过高炉烧制后
我们使用离心机来分离出那些锑粉
但这些材料纯度仍然很低
所以我们得加点调味料，如P-507
如你所见
我们已经获得了高纯度的硅岩粉了
正因为我们使用的P-507质量上乘
它是通过人工种植有机坚果
提取其油分制成的
最后一步将其通入中子活化器
让其在我们齿颊留香
然而
我们缺少完成这步骤所需的烹饪工具
想要获取一个的话
我们需要一个精密组装机
但制作它
我们需要一些硅岩掺杂的晶圆
因为便利店不提供售卖服务
所以我们得先用土法制硅岩
有了这些不入流方法获得的硅岩
我们将能制作出第一台精密组装机
然而
那只是主方块
我们还需要一堆电子机械外壳
而同时一个难题接踵而至
我们需要一台 LuV 级组装机
所以我想我们应该回到主线
开始做通向 LuV 的装配线
但我觉得这值得单独出一集
所以再见~
（最新版已禁止此方法）
（臭名昭著的镧系处理）
（除了具有铁磁性的铁钴镍以外，其他元素构成的化合物对磁场的反应微弱）
LuV